If the rating is 4, then we'll pass our first if test.
إن كان التقييم 4، فسنمر من اختبار if الأول.
Because 4 is between 0 and 5.
لأن 4 تقع بين صفر وخمسة.
Then, we move on to our second nested if and test if rating is less than or equal to 2.
ثم ننتقل إلى if الثانية المتداخلة ونتفحص ما إذا كان التقييم أقل من أو يساوي 2.
Since rating is 4, it's not lower than 2,
بما أن التقييم هو 4، فهو ليس أقل من 2.
this is false, and we do not enter this block of code.
هذا خطأ، "false"، ولن ندخل كتلة التعليمات البرمجية هذه.
Instead, we'll skip to its ending curly brace and after this curly brace,
بل سنتخطاها إلى قوسها المتعرج النهائي. وبعد القوس المتعرج هذا،
there's a print line that prints out,
يوجد سطر print يطبع
"Thank you for your feedback".
"شكراً لك على ملاحظاتك".
So that's all that will print out for when our rating is equal to 4.
هذا كل ما سيُطبع عندما يكون التقييم 4.
If the rating was lower,
إذا كانت قيمة التقييم أقل،
something like 1, we would pass through both our if tests,
كأن تكون 1 مثلاً، فسنمر من اختباري if.
and because we're reading line by line,
ولأننا نقرأ سطراُ تلو الآخر،
you go into our nested if first,
فسننفذ ما في if المتداخلة أولاً
and print out "What's the reason for your low rating?"
ونطبع "ما سبب تقييمك المتدني؟".
Then when we exit it, we'd print out,
ثم نطبع عند خروجنا:
"Thank you for your feedback".
"شكراً لك على ملاحظاتك".
So if rating was equal to 1,
إذن، إذا كان التقييم يساوي 1،
we'd print out both of these lines.
فسنطبع كلا السطرين.
But for rating equals 4,
لكن إن كان التقييم يساوي 4،
we just print out, "Thank you for your feedback".
فسنطبع "شكراً لك على ملاحظاتك".
So nested if statements can be very useful when you want to do something
يمكن لعبارات if المتداخلة أن تكون مفيدة جداً عندما تريد القيام بشيء فريد
unique within the nested if block of code versus outside.
داخل كتلة التعليمات البرمجية لـif المتداخلة بدلاً من خارجها.